Theodor Florian Purcaru

Software Developer at SkyadsMedia ApS

greenbluebit@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a Full Stack Developer, always trying to improve, learn to use new tools and make shortcuts to increase efficiency for future projects (my affinity for plugins can attest to that). I've worked on many projects along the time I've been part of the industry which gives me enough perspective to say about myself that I thrive on problems, especially if someone tells me it's impossible. I also like change. This makes me fit great on projects where the requirements are in constant flux and the team focuses on agile methodologies. At the end of the day, I love my job, I can't describe the feeling when a customer tells me their new system has increased their productivity or that their partners are jealous of the way they do their work now. Makes me feel I've made a difference. If you want to chat more, contact me at greenbluebit@gmail.com

Experience

Software Developer at SkyCloud

June 2015 - Present (4 months)

I work full time creating some great products.

Software Developer at BlueBit

January 2013 - Present (2 years 9 months)

Created Bluebit -- a start-up company to consolidate my work with Austeja Vaicyte. Our projects are diverse, ranging from applications to games or automatons.

System Developer at S23

December 2014 - February 2015 (3 months)

Developed an administration system with Laravel for daily use with limited access for partners and customers to check on projects related to their own businesses.

Intern at Vaizdine Reklama

August 2014 - January 2015 (6 months)

Created a data logging application for customers and products as well as solutions for different day to day activities. e.g. pi based smart cameras and servers. Maintained computers and software. Co-built a method to shorten a url using php which included statistics and tracking capabilities, capable of modifying the destination, etc.

Computer Specialist at PrintSign

November 2013 - July 2014 (9 months)

I worked part time for 10 hours a week, fixing all problems that can appear regarding their computers, clean them, reinstall software, administrate their servers and website etc. I also built software solutions for day to day operations.

Junior Computer Specialist at Vaizdine Reklama

September 2013 - December 2013 (4 months)

I had a part time job as IT support for their administration system which I created, server and website maintenance and fixing general tech related problems.

1 recommendation available upon request

System Developer at Vaizdine Reklama

February 2013 - June 2013 (5 months)

Created a system to maintain and administer day to day operations

Volunteer at The Salvation Army

February 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Assisted with the friday free cantina, the friday karaoke bar, donated electric devices and clothes, helped in donated items distribution and taught children to play instruments

Lead magazine editor at Romanian Institute Of Education

September 2010 - July 2012 (1 year 11 months)

Created a magazine to promote English culture and the talents of students in my city. I had 2 people in my team

Honors and Awards

People's Choice

Microsoft

April 2014

During the Microsoft Innovation Cup, our team received the People's Choice Award for creating the product most wanted by the entire audience. The whole experience was very educative, offered a lot of needed input and was an all around fun thing to do.

Denmark level finalists

Microsoft

May 2014

In the Imagine Cup, team Macaw got the chance to give a presentation to a great audience before being treated to a concert with Wafande. We had the chance to be judged by great names in the Industry and to experience presenting our ideas at a much higher level.

Award for Best Sound

Arsenalet

April 2015

Won best sound for the game we created during the Easter Jam. To check out the soundtrack and the old prototype, follow this link: http://gamejolt.com/games/adventure/you-won-t-believe-what-happens-next/58125/

Award for Best Sound, Best Visuals and Jack of All Trades

Summer Game Jam

August 2015

http://tandems.itch.io/far-beyond - a game where you get lost in the Antarctic.

Projects

Spritest

April 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

Created a web app that allows artists to create and use spritesheets easily, or to test existing sheets for animations, create gifs, and share with team.

DropLoader

May 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

Was looking for a way to drop files in any html element and then have access to them w/o having to first save the files to the server. Wasn't able to find any plugin for this so I created one. It works very simply, and it also gives you the ability to do whatever you want with the files after what your task was, so for example, you can modify them somehow (in my case, put a watermark on images) and then send them to the server.

Incremental

April 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

Incremental is a plugin that gives the ability to easily add a + and - button with a few quick features I found myself always needing to implement manually on most of my web projects.

Draggable

February 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

Make any element in html scrollable by just clicking and dragging the mouse.

HaiCraiova

February 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

A simple web app that displays events based on your current location. If you're insecure with sharing that information or if you simple want to check another place, you can do that too. It also allows you to book tickets at any events that has them.

You won't Believe What Happens Next

April 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte, Mark Nielsen, Jonas Kappel Lund

Created this game during the Arsenalet Game Jam. It's a dungeon crawler where the player has to battle different monsters with a few twists.

SafeLight

December 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

SafeLight - a cute torch app with minimalist design and requirements.

Johny OFive

April 2013 to May 2013

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

I created an autonomous RC from scrap I found around my town, an arduino board and a proximity sensor

ElemEdit

October 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

A small jquery plugin that turns any html element into an editable input field. Can then send the modifications back to any backend. Great for example to modify data displayed in a table.

Terminal_Plugin

April 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

This jQuery plugin allows you to have an old style CRT monitor drawn on your website with a terminal interface and any custom functionality with just 1 line of code. Quick examples I whipped out: http://demos.bluebit.nu/elite terminal/ http://demos.bluebit.nu/terminal/

Adam

March 2013 to April 2013

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

Adam is an event gatherer and emulator which works on the windows platform. It can help with presentations, or to automate repetitive jobs.

Async_change

March 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

This plugin allows any web element to be in a contstant change with just a few lines of code, from the favicon to a heading, anything can be easily animated.

WhatIf?

September 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

A very simple twitter like web app which I then transferred to mobile. Allows people to shout out their opinions in a fun way and then comment them with others. The resulting conversations have ranged from funny to disturbing.

Raspberry Pi webserver

November 2013 to November 2013

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

A company needed a quick solution for file transfer between their offices for fast production within a limited time frame and with a tight to no budget. Using a Raspberry Pi and an external HDD, they now have a nice webserver, with a decent transfer speed which fits their needs perfectly.

BlueBit-Framework

November 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

A basic responsive theme framework for WordPress which allows anyone to build any website very quickly. See following example: http://austeja.bluebit.nu/

MomChat

May 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

Created this chat for my mom, works on computers and smart phones alike. My mom kept complaining I m not on skype when she is => her messages wouldn't sync so I would never see she wrote to me. This program saves all the conversations on a server so when anyone connects it immediately pulls everything from there, regardless if the user saw it before or not. Of course I regretted this project immediately, as my mom could now write to me constantly, and I could not use the skype excuse anymore.

VRSystem

June 2013 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

This system allows the company to keep track of all their work, equipment, deliveries and employees. It also has statistics, alerts and other few nifty tools the CEO thought about.

Pleasant Weather

October 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

This app allows you to see the weather in any city you'd like together with extra information like humidity and pressure. Add to that a nice color scheme and a few jokes in between the lines and you have yourself a pleasant way to know what to wear at all times.

Killer Demon Tiny Cat

August 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru, Austeja Vaicyte

We created the game for our niece to play on the phone while we're at work. The idea is to pet the cat to keep it happy and how it complains if you ignore it.

Fresh Tomatoes

April 2014 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

A simple website with fully written administration side which I created for my udacity course.

Swiss Tournament

May 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

Fully fleshed backend which can handle swiss styled tournaments for any kind of game.

Horror Scripting Demo

June 2015 to Present

Members: Theodor Florian Purcaru

Just a small project where I practice c#. Created it as an example to quickly show off my level when I look for partners during gamejams.

Volunteer Experience

Helper at The Salvation Army

January 2011 - May 2011 (5 months)

I helped whenever I could, bringing whatever I could think of that could help the people affected of poverty, such as food, clothes, as well as things for children to enjoy, toys, games etc. I also sometimes helped the music classes and helped cooking for the poor.

Game Tester at Interceptor Entertainment

May 2015 - Present (5 months)

Went to their offices and had a lot of fun while trying out their new stuff. Can't say much other then the fact that it's pretty dang impressive.

Courses

Computer Science AP

Copenhagen Business Academy

Computer Science

AP, Computer Science

University College of Northern Denmark

Computer Science

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency) **Romanian** (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Danish (Elementary proficiency)

Italian (Elementary proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

CSS

Databases

Programming

HTML

Microsoft Office

Java

C++, Java, mySQL, Microsoft SQL, 3D max,

blender

Coding Experience

Management

Microsoft Excel

HTML5

Windows

JavaScript

Software Documentation

JPA

Humor

jQuery

CSS3

OOP

RESTful WebServices

Microsoft Visual Studio C++

Eclipse

HTML 5

Working Experience

AJAX

Web Servers

C++

Access

Windows 7

Servers

OS X

Ubuntu

Apache

Operating Systems

Visual Basic

PHP

Software Development

MySQL

Web Development

System Administration

SQL

Android

PostgreSQL

Education

Udacity

Full Stack Developer Nanodegree, Computer Science, 2015 - 2015

Copenhagen Business Academy

Computer Science AP, 2013 - 2015

Activities and Societies: The incubator, Microsoft meetings for the Imagine Cup and Innovation Cup

1 recommendation available upon request

University College of Northern Denmark

AP, Computer Science, 2012 - 2013

Activities and Societies: Game Club - Where we made games (and played them)

Liceul Teoretic Henri Coanda

Highschool, 2008 - 2012

Activities and Societies: Photography Club, Computer Club, Theater Club, Poetry Club, School Magazine

Theodor Florian Purcaru

Software Developer at SkyadsMedia ApS

greenbluebit@gmail.com



2 people have recommended Theodor Florian

"Teodor has wide experience in different fields of programming. He has the right work spirit, sees everything as a challenge and not a problem. Get things done/fast typer. Very creative in programming. His code is clean. He is a fantastic person to work with, has great sense of humor and makes you feel like a team mate! I highly recommend Theodor as a programmer"

— Per Johannessen, Student, Cphbusiness, worked directly with Theodor Florian at Vaizdine Reklama

"He probably paid those people to endorse him for those skills."

— Adrian Bordinc, advised Theodor Florian

Contact Theodor Florian on LinkedIn